Guide to the Cosmetics Trade Samples and Sachet collection, 1890s-1930s RL.11349
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cosmetics Trade Samples and Sachet collection
1890s-1930s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.11349
1.0 Linear Feet
Consists of 75 trade samples and sachets of cosmetics, powders, makeup, soaps and scented paraphernalia. Companies are primarily based in the United States, but Canadian and French perfumers are also represented, including Andrew Jergens, California Perfume (later Avon), Colgate, Frederick Ingram, Furst-McNess, Johnson & Johnson, Larkin, Lehn & Fink and Richard Hudnut. Poems and testimonials on packaging from Ethel Barrymore, Kate Greenaway, Mrs. Leslie Carter and Modjeska. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History and the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by company name.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Cosmetics Trade Samples and Sachet collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2014.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman and Bingham Center collections:
Advertising Ephemera collection; Bates Worldwide, Inc. records; J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files; Max Factor Make-up Studio collection; Studio Girl Cosmetics records.
Collection Overview
Consists of 75 trade samples and sachets of cosmetics, powders, makeup, soaps and scented paraphernalia. Companies are primarily based in the United States, but Canadian and French perfumers are also represented, including Andrew Jergens, California Perfume (later Avon), Colgate, Frederick Ingram, Furst-McNess, Johnson & Johnson, Larkin, Lehn & Fink and Richard Hudnut. Poems and testimonials on packaging from Ethel Barrymore, Kate Greenaway, Mrs. Leslie Carter and Modjeska. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History and the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Cosmetics; Advertising -- Cosmetics; Perfume industry; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Andrew Jergens Company (Cincinnati, Ohio); Colgate-Palmolive Company; Johnson & Johnson; Lehn & Fink
- A.G. Schleuter, 1
  - Floralia face powder, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0001)
    Scope and Contents
    A.G. Schlueter, E. St. Louis, Mo. Slogan "For Beautifying the complexion perfectly harmless."
- A.P. Babcock Co., 2
  - Babcock's Corylopsis of Japan Sachet, Superfine Highest Quality, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0002)
    A.P. Babcock Co., New York
  - Cut Roses Sachet Highest Concentration, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0003)
- Abert F. Wood, 3
  - Satin Skin Compexion Powder, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0004)
    Albert F. Wood, Detroit, Mich. Text: "A Free Packet of Satin Skin Complexion Powder; Adhesive, Invisible, harmless; Adds charming fairness, a gossamer glow of refinement. To beautify, tone down, remove shiny, oily appearance, secure a smooth satin skin, use Satin Skin Complexion Powder (4 tints) 25c. boxes. Natural flesh, Brilliant white, Rich pink, Perfect brunette." Text on reverse: "A dainty, feathery, beautifying application like Satin Skin Powder keeps the skin young, fresh and fair long after it would become coarse and uninviting, if neglected. Use Satin Skin Powder with the assurance that it is positively innocent and harmless in action. Only soothing, revivifying and a skin preservative of unusual merit and true worth."
- Andrew Jergens, 4
  - Jergens Doris Borated Toilet Powder, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0005)
    Andrew Jergens Co. Cincinnati--New York. Text: "Doris Toilet Water is put up in beautiful ornamental opaque glass containers, which are refillable. It is a perfect powder (imported) of the finest texture, prepared with boric acid and other ingredients, making it appropriate for face and general usage. It is made in Rose and Violet odors and Flesh and White tints."
  - Jergens Doris Borated Toilet Powder, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0006)
  - Jergens Doris Poudre de Riz rice powder, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0007)
    Andrew Jergens Co. Cincinnati--New York. Text: "It is guaranteed perfectly harmless and absorbes (sic) the moisture. Produces the velvety softness and delicate bloom of youth."
- Bauer & Black, 5
  - B&B Beauty Spots Assorted Shapes, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0008)
    Bauer & Black, Chicago.
  - B&B Beauty Spots Assorted Shapes, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0009)
- Bronson Chemical Co., 6
  - Zenobia Sachet, 1880s-1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0010)
    Bronson Chemical Co., Providence, R.I. "Floreal" stamped on reverse.
  - Zenobia Sachet, 1880s-1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0011)
    Bronson Chemical Co., Providence, R.I. "Victoire (x) 1" hand-written on reverse.
  - Zenobia Sachet, 1880s-1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0012)
    Bronson Chemical Co., Providence, R.I. "Violette (x) 1" hand-written on reverse.
- California Perfume Co., 7
  - Sachet Powder Violet, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0013)
    California Perfume Co., New York. (founded 1886; renamed 1939 as Avon Products)
  - Sachet Powder Heliotrope, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0014)
- Chapman & Rodgers, Inc., 8
  - Quentin's Beauty Leaves for the Complexion blotting paper, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0015)
    Chapman & Rodgers, Inc., Philadelphia. Booklet. Text on back cover: "Beauty Leaves. A specially prepared absorbent chamois-finished paper, coated with a delightfully perfumed face powder, containing only ingredients of the purest quality and best-known asceptic properties. Absolutely free from all injurious substances. Applied gently it removes dust and oily secretions from the surface of the skin, giving it a beautifully soft pearly appearance, and producing a cool refreshing feeling. An examination of the leaf after using will show how the paper has removed the oil and dust, which by the use of the old style puff were simply covered. Can be conveniently carried in the pocket book and used without the aid of a mirror. Gentlemen will find it handy for use after shaving, especially when traveling. Guaranteed by the manufacturers, Chapman & Rodgers, Inc., under the Food and Drugs Act, June 30, 1906. No. 2961."
- Charles Meyer, 9
  - Exora Mascarillo, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0016)
    Charles Meyer, New York. Text: "Free Sample Black Charles Meyer New York Originator of Black Exora Mascarillo for Darkening Eyebrows, Eye Lashes, Beards and Hair. By All First Class Toilet Goods Dealers." Text on reverse: "Exora Mascarillo: Black--Dark Brown--Medium Brown--Light Brown--Auburn--Blonde--Titian. Apply with moist brush to hair which must not be greasy. Comb hair still damp, when dry dress hair. Removed with soap and water. Established 1868."
  - Exora Rouge, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0017)
    Charles Meyer, New York. Text: "Free Sample Darkest Charles Meyer New York Originator of Exora Rouge. By All First Class Toilet Goods Dealers." Text on reverse: "Exora Rouge: Darkest--Dark--Medium--Light--Natural. Guaranteed harmless, does not contain any injurious or poisonous chemicals, entirely vegetable and not affected by water or perspiration. Established 1868."
- Chicago Sachet Works, 10
  - Doris Grey Sachet. Carnation, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0018)
    Chicago Sachet Works, Chicago.
- Colgate & Co., 11
  - Cashmere Bouquet, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0019)
    Colgate & Co. Perfumers, New York.
- Frederick F. Ingram Co., 12
  - Ingram's Rouge (Brunette) Guest Room Size, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0020)
    Frederick F. Ingram Co., Windsor, Ontario and Detroit, Mich. (Incorporated under that name 1909) Text: Full size in handsome telescope leatherette box, with silk and wool powder pad for applying. Two Shades--Brunette and Flesh. Either shade may be used, regardless of complexion, but it is best to use the shade best suited for the shade of the complexion. Price 50 cents."
- Freeman Perfume Company, 13
  - Freeman's Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0021)
    Freeman Perfume Company, Cincinnati and New York. Sample of white face powder. Slogans "It's Freeman's" and "Freeman's Face Powder The Best Because It's Good for the Skin"; testimonial images of Leslie Carter (Caroline Louise Dudley) and Modjeska. For sale by Dr. Theo W. Koldeway Druggist, 2 Frederick Ave.
  - Freeman's Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0022)
    Freeman Perfume Company, Cincinnati. Sample of brunette face powder. Slogan "It's Freeman's" on front. Reverse: The name Freeman on Face Powder Means Highest Quality.
  - Freeman's Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0023)
    Freeman Perfume Company, Cincinnati. Sample of white face powder. Slogans "It's Freeman's Face Powder" and "The Kind Mamma Uses" on front. Testimonials from Leslie Carter, Ethel Barrymore and others on reverse. For sale by G.E.B. Fairbanks Druggist, Providence, R.I.
  - Freeman's Violet Talcum, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0024)
    Freeman Perfume Co., Cincinnati. Text on reverse explains difference between talcum and face powders. Offer for a sample of Freeman's Face Powder. For sale by G.E.B. Fairbanks Druggist, Providence, R.I.
  - Freeman's Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0025)
    Freeman Perfume Company, Cincinnati. Sample of pink face powder. Slogans "It's Freeman's Face Powder" and "The Kind Mamma Uses" on front. Testimonials from Leslie Carter, Ethel Barrymore and others on reverse.
  - Freeman's Violet Talcum, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0026)
  - Freeman's Face Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0027)
- Furst-McNess Co., 14
  - ReJois Face Powder, 1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0028)
    Furst-McNess Co., founded 1908 in Freeport, Ill. Text: "Re Jois Before You Go. Free Sample ReJois Face Powder."
- Henry Tetlow/Tetlow Perfume Company, 15
  - Tetlow's Gossamer for the Complexion., 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0029)
    Henry Tetlow/Tetlow Perfume Company, Philadelphia. Cover text "Held Up! For Public Approval/Has Stood the test for 30 years. Tetlow's Gossamer for the Complexion; Delightfully Perfumed Imparts a Radiant Bloom; Absolutely Pure and Harmless Dainty Refined; Endorsed by the Medical Profession. Reverse: Soothes Nourishes; Makes the Skin Feel Well Cared For. For sale by S.S. Lightbody, Waterville Maine.
  - Tetlow's Gossamer for the Complexion., 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0030)
    Henry Tetlow/Tetlow Perfume Company, Philadelphia. Flesh tint. Cover text "Delightfully Perfumed Imparts a Radiant Bloom; Absolutely Pure and Harmless. Dainty Refined." Compliments of Adam's Drug Store, Reading, Pa.
  - Henry Tetlow's Blue Moon Talcum, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0031)
    Henry Tetlow Company, Philadelphia. Includes offer of a free box of Blue Moon Face Powder for recommending the product to friends.
- Hygienol Company, 16
  - Peter Pan Stitchless Wool Powder Puff, 1930s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0032)
    Hygienol Company, New Rochelle, N.Y. (incorporated 1929) Text: "Contents of Plush Fabric--100% Virgin Wool Pile--100% Cotton Back--Pile 71% of Fabric--Back 20% of Fabric."
- Indianapolis Soap Co., 17
  - Oriental Oils Vegetable Soap, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0033)
    Indianapolis Soap Co., Indianapolis, Ind. "For improving the complexion. A Pure White Vegetable Oil Soap Free from all animal fats or other impurities, delicately scented. For Cleansing and Purifying the skin."
- Johnson & Johnson, 18
  - Johnson's Baby Powder, 1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0034)
    Johnson & Johnson, New Brunswick, N.J. Slogans on front "Best for Baby, Best for You; Keep Baby's Tender Skin Comfortable; For Your Baby Who Deserves the Best" Text on reverse: "Mother's Own Reasons for preferring Johnson's Baby Powder because it: Heals--is safe and pure; soothes; helps sleep; prevents chafing; does not clog pores; is best for family. Johnson's Baby Powder is made to give only that cooling, soothing comfort so necessary to baby's tender skin, constantly tormented by itches and irritations. You want the best powder for your baby. You get it in Johnson's."
- L.H. Peirson, 19
  - Peirson's California Orange Blossom Sachet Powder, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0035)
    L.H. Peirson, Los Angeles, Calif.
- La Maison Dorin, 20
  - Dorin Rouge Framboise No. 1251., 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0036)
    La Maison Dorin, Paris. Sole Agents F.R. Arnold & Co., New York. Text: "Rouge Framboise--A delicately perfumed compact Powder in box with puff, especially invented for dark complexions--Guaranteed Harmless."
  - Dorin Rouge Brunette No. 1249., 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0037)
    La Maison Dorin, Paris. Sole Agents F.R. Arnold & Co., New York. Text: "Rouge Brunette--A compact rouge in box with puff, delicately perfumed, has a peculiar quality of lending a natural, healthy glow to all complexions, Blonde or Brunette, guaranteed harmless."
  - Dorin Rouge Naturel No. 1250, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0038)
    La Maison Dorin, Paris. Sole Agents F.R. Arnold & Co., New York. Text: "Rouge naturel--A compact rouge in box with puff, delicately perfumed. Especially prepared for Blond complexions to which it imparts the desired tint of health."
  - Dorin La Dorine Fleur de Riz Compacte Naturelle No. 124, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0039)
    La Maison Dorin, Paris. Sole Agents F.R. Arnold & Co., New York. Text: "La Dorine fleur de Riz compacte no. 124--Supplied in Blanche, Rose, Naturelle, Rachel, Olivette. A compact Face Powder exquisitely perfumed in box with puff. Quality unexcelled. Supplied also in large Etuis for Toilet Table (Nos. 119, 119B)"
  - Dorin Rouge Framboise No. 1251., 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0040)
- Ladd & Coffin, 21
  - Lundborg's Violet Sachet, 1890s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0041)
    [Ladd & Coffin] No other identifying material on envelope.
- Larkin Co., 22
  - Sandal Wood Sachet Powder, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0042)
    Larkin Co. Inc. Perfumers, Buffalo, N.Y.
  - Sandal Wood Sachet Powder, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0043)
  - Carnation Sachet, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0044)
  - Carnation Sachet, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0045)
  - Violet Sachet, 1914 (Box 1, Item RL11349-0046)
- Lehn & Fink Perfumers, 23
  - Lehn & Fink's Riveris Talcum Powder, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0047)
    Lehn & Fink Perfumers, New York. (Acquired by Sterling Drug in 1967; by AG Bayer in 1994) Text: "Scented with the essence of Riviera Violets--A luxury for the lady's toilet table. A necessity for the baby's health and comfort delightful after shaving." Reverse text: "This is a Sample Only. Other side of this envelope is facsimile in size and color of the regular glass jar. Riveris Talcum Powder answers the purpose of a general Toilet Powder. It is light and fluffy if properly applied to the skin. The only Talcum Powder fine enough for use with powder puff. If your dealer does not carry this powder in stock, INSIST upon his getting it for you from his wholesaler."
- Leonin Co., 24
  - Leonin Bouquet Sachet Perfume., 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0048)
    Leonin Co., St. Louis, Mo. Leonin Perfume Sachet Packet No. 6718. Slogan on front "The Sweetest and most Fragrant Perfume in Existence made from Natural Flowers." Offer on reverse for gold plated stone set ring.
- Milson Company, 25
  - Healtho Tut Fleurs Narcissus Face Powder, 1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0049)
    Health Bonded Products, The Milson Company, Cincinnati, Ohio. Text: "Try this free sample of Health-O Tut Fleurs flesh face powder, price per box 50c. This is my introduction to you. I will call on you regularly every few weeks. Kindly tell your friends how well you like HEALTH-O Products. You will be doing them a favor if you show them the exceptional values you obtained. Thank You! You will find every HEALTH-O Product as satisfying and economical as this trial package of this most famous Face Powder. TUT FLEURS NARCISSE the finest and purest. All HEALTH-O preparations are sold on a money back guarantee, and can only be purchased from our authorized representatives. You can purchase a full size box of This Delightful Face Powder or any of our more than 250 HEALTH-O Products from me."
- Miss A.C. Graves, creator, 26
  - Agnesian Face Powder, undated (Box 1, Item RL11349-0050)
    "Put up by Miss A.C. Graves, Goldsmith Building, Milwaukee, Wis." (The Goldsmith Building, built in 1893 and demolished 1982, was located at 425 E. Wisconsin Ave.) Text: "Agnesian Trade Mark (sith symbol of St. Agnes) Use Agnesian Softenwhite before powdering. It holds the powder and prevents burning or chapping. 25 cents."
- Moore Bros. Company, 27
  - Purity Soap Leaves, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0051)
    Moore Bros. Company (a Corporation, established 1890), New York. Booklet. Text: "Moore's Soap Leaves. Made up in book form for the vest pocket or for the ladies' hand bag. Carry your own individual soap, tear out a leaf, rub it between wet hands and see how it lathers--it cleans perfectly--leaves the skin soft and smooth--makes one feel good after using. A Superior Soap put up in this Peculiar Manner. Personification of convenience. Indispensable to travelers, cyclists and automobilists. An absolute necessity for Commercial Men, Tourists, Train Men and General Public." Text on back cover: "A unique sanitary invention commending itself to all. A purely vegetable leaf toilet soap. Combining utility, convenience and economy. Each leaf a wash. Use same as any soap. Try it for shampoo. No better soap made. Free from animal fats."
  - Purity Soap Leaves, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0052)
- National Drug and Chemical Company of Canada, 28
  - Na-Dru-Co Talcum Powder, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0053)
    National Drug and Chemical Company of Canada, Limited. (Renamed Nadruco Holdings Limited in 1980; acquired by Provigo Inc. 1981 which became a subsidiary of Loblaw Companies Ltd. In 1999) Text: "Can be obtained from all dealers. It is supplied in three elegant and distinctly colored containers. Borated, Violet, and Flesh. This is a sample of Flesh. Ask for NA-DRU-CO"
- Papier Poudré Ltd., 29
  - Lehcaresor Papier Poudré Rachel blotting paper, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0054)
    Papier Poudré Ltd, London and Paris (founded 1903, still in business). Booklet, instructions in English and French on inside cover. Text: "The Latest Toilet Novelty. Beware of Worthless Imitations. None genuine unless bearing our Trade Mark, and our Name. Sole Agents for the U.S.A.: P.R. Arnold & Co., New York." Back cover text: "Papier Poudré. A delicately perfumed preparation for the skin. The paper has the peculiar quality of being absorbent. It is invaluable when the face becomes moist and flushed--at the play, at receptions, when shopping, calling, motoring, bicycling or travelling, and at all sorts of odd moments. It can be used without a mirror, and without fear of sprinkling the corsage with powder. It removes dust, smuts, and grease from the face, imparting a cool delicate bloom, without clogging the pores. It acts as a tonic to the skin. It is most pleasant to use after shaving, leaving the skin smooth and cool. It is absolutely harmless."
- Parfumeur Trevaux, 30
  - Salut d'Amour Sachet. Bouquet de Fleurs., 1930s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0055)
    Parfumeur Trevaux, Chicago. Instructions for use on reverse.
  - Salut d'Amour Sachet. Bouquet de Fleurs., 1930s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0056)
- Pompeian Company, 31
  - Pompeian Bloom, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0057)
    Pompeian Company, Cleveland, Ohio. Tint Medium shade. Text: "Pompeian BLOOM for Youthful Color. Youthful Beauty can be obtained by the right use of Pompeian BLOOM. Distribute the color well over the cheeks. Get a natural bloom of youth, not a conspicuous effect. Made in a cake that won't break. Light, Dark, and Medium shades. GUARANTEE: Should you not be completely satisfied with any Pompeian Preparation, the purchase price with be gladly refunded by The Pompeian Company."
  - Pompeian Bloom, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0058)
    Pompeian Company, Cleveland, Ohio. Tint Medium shade. Text: "Comes in Cake Form. This sample Medium Shade (Made also in light and dark). Roses in the Cheeks. Try Pompeian DAY Cream and Pompeian BEAUTY Powder."
  - Pompeian Beauty Powder, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0059)
    Pompeian Company, Cleveland, Ohio. Text: "Flesh Shade (Also made in White and Brunette) Stays on unusually long. Its Fragrance captivates. Try Pompeian DAY Cream and Pompeian BLOOM (a rouge)"
  - Pompeian Fragrance Talc, 1900s-1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0060)
    Pompeian Company, Cleveland, Ohio.
- Prichard and Constance, 32
  - Amami Bouquet Talcum, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0061)
    Prichard and Constance, London and New York. "Perfumers by royal appointment to the queen of the Belgians." Text: "Amami Talcum may be obtained at most high class stores in beautiful 25c. boxes. Amami Talcum is always appropriate. Its elusive, yet persistent fragrance breathes dainty refinement."
- Puritan Pharmaceutical Co., 33
  - "Puritan Beauty" face powder, flesh tint., 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0062)
    Puritan Pharmaceutical Co., St. Louis, Mo. Slogan on front "The Guaranteed Line." Text: "A delightfully perfumed and most pleasing Face Powder of sterling value--as fine and soft as down. It adheres closely to the skin, imparting a dainty fragrance and a soft youthful appearance without showing powder. Positively will not irritate the most delicate skin. Satisfaction guaranteed or money refunded. For sale by all dealers or by mail." Text on reverse promotes a range of Puritan Beauty cosmetics.
- Red Feather Perfume Co., 34
  - Red Feather Face Powder, 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0063)
    Red Feather Perfume Co., New York. [Owl Drug Company] Text on reverse: "Free Sample Penalty for Sale $500"
- Richard Hudnut, 35
  - Three Flowers Face Powder, 1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0064)
    Richard Hudnut, New York and Paris. Naturelle Color tint. Contains small metal container of powder. Text inside: "Dear Madam: Richard Hudnut THREE FLOWERS FACE POWDER clings tenaciously to the skin and gives that youthful bloom so universally admired. It wins a lasting popularity with women of cultured taste because of the absolute purity of the ingredients and for the attractive and pleasant fragrance of Three Flowers. Will you not test for yourself the merits of this superb powder by using this small sample? Respectfully, Richard Hudnut." Instructions for use on back, "The Art of Applying Face Powder."
- Sovereign Perfumes, 36
  - Corson's Ideal Orchid Talcum, 1910s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0065)
    Sovereign Perfumes Ltd., Toronto Canada. Text: "This wee envelope contains a whiff of something lovely, as delicate as the daintiest spring wild flowers. Prepared from the most expensive talc--it is impalpably fine and soft. 25c. at better Druggists."
- Unidentified, 37
  - Tnamras lasting sachet Peau d'Espagne, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0066)
    No other identifying material on envelope.
  - Alice May Sachet, Lilac Blossoms, Fragrant and Lasting, 1920s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0067)
  - California Flowers Sachet, undated (Box 1, Item RL11349-0068)
  - Tnamras lasting sachet Peau d'Espagne, 1900s (Box 1, Item RL11349-0069)